<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>-- MARKET -- Real Estate Video Blog with Lela Ashkarian &amp; Natalie Ardis</title>
    <description>Our mission at Luxury Island Properties is to be your best resource for  real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Luxury Island Properties, your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 10:27:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 10:27:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in the Keys Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RhUg-Mu7MB8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in for the Florida Keys real estate market and I’m excited to share them with you today. Compared to last year, there was quite a change in the numbers. &lt;strong&gt;All of these statistics are through the end of February 2021 as compared to February 2020:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Florida Keys sales have increased 55.7%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average sale price is up 44% to right around $860,000 Keys-wide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Days on market is stable—right around 111 days. This may start to trend downward in the next few months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pending transactions (i.e. when a property goes under contract) are up 61% over last year. We had 714 properties under contract at the end of February 2021 compared to 441 in February 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s more important than ever for homebuyers to have a professional by their side.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-the-keys-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s more important than ever for homebuyers to have a professional by their side.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep in mind that the numbers from 2020 are pre-COVID, so in the next few months we should really start to see how the market has recovered from that time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredible to see just how different today’s market is from where we were a year ago. More homes are selling for more money, which is great news for home sellers. As for homebuyers, these numbers mean that the stiff competition is even stiffer, so it’s more important than ever to have a professional on your side who can help you win against multiple offers. If you have any specific questions about the numbers in your neighborhood or anything related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 13:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-the-keys-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-the-keys-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Options for Low Appraisals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a6qavDvNomU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appraisers use past sales in your home’s area as comparable properties to determine their valuation of your home. So what should you do if your home’s appraisal comes in lower than your contract price? There are a few options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Look at the comparable properties&lt;/strong&gt; that were used to see if there were any errors made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Submit a rebuttal.&lt;/strong&gt; Talk to your lender about a rebuttal; it could be that there are some comparables that were missed that could influence the appraisal. However, the rebuttal process can be challenging and often doesn’t pan out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. See if the buyer is willing to cover the difference&lt;/strong&gt; between the appraised value and the contract price. Essentially, that would be a larger down payment toward their loan. Verify with your lender that you’re in the position to go this route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Renegotiate.&lt;/strong&gt; If nothing else, you could try to negotiate a price in the sweet spot between the appraised value and contract price, one that both parties are amenable to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that in Florida, if the appraisal of the property obtained by the buyer’s lender is insufficient to meet the terms of the loan approval, then the buyer shall be refunded their deposit and they can cancel the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our current market or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:04:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-options-for-low-appraisals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-options-for-low-appraisals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Balance Between List Price &amp; Sale Price</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9JxMW08_-kg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Keys buyer, how much of the list price should you offer? If you’re a seller looking to stir up activity on your listing, what does our market tell us is a normal list-to-sale price reduction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Most sellers can expect a total list-to-sale price reduction of around 9%.%20http://localhost:4000/the-balance-between-list-price-sale-price.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Most sellers can expect a total list-to-sale price reduction of around 9%.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers who don’t see enough activity during the initial term of their listing (i.e., few showings and no offers) likely need a price reduction. In our area, &lt;strong&gt;it usually takes an average price reduction of 5% off of sellers’ original list to get offers flowing in.&lt;/strong&gt; Then, depending on the marketplace, we’re seeing buyers come within 4% to 5% of that new list price. That means most sellers can expect a total list-to-sale price reduction of around 9%, though that figure varies from the Upper Keys down to Key West. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, if you’re a buyer who’s discussing a property’s history with your agent, you’ll first want to check if there have been any price reductions. If a property is priced quite aggressively or you see that there’s been a fairly standard price reduction, then you’ll know that coming in at 4% off of list price—that Keys-wide average—is a strong place to start. Naturally, everyone wants to negotiate for as much as they can get, but avoid lowballing the seller. To have a seller counter your offer is normal, but you don’t want to come in so low that the mere thought of humoring your offer is offensive to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, reach out by phone or email if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic. My partner Lela and I are happy to be resources for you and assist with whatever buying, selling, or investing needs you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 12:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-balance-between-list-price-sale-price.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-balance-between-list-price-sale-price.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Did 2020 Leave Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/It7CTGK-R_8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we make our way through the first month of 2021, we find that &lt;strong&gt;our market is still going very strong.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually here in the Keys, we see an uptick in the number of listings in the first quarter of the year. So far, that anticipated increase has been a small one, as our inventory remains extremely low compared to previous years—a trend that rings true for most markets across the country right now. Here’s how we wrapped up 2020: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keys-wide sales rose 16.6% compared to 2019.&lt;/strong&gt; Some areas recorded even more dramatic increases, like the Middle Keys, which enjoyed a dominant 30% increase. Our average sales price increased by 8.5% and is now hovering close to $671,000. How low, exactly, is our inventory? Compared to 2019, we finished 2020 down an astounding 24%. It’s an inverse relationship; whenever our listing inventory is down, our sales increase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason to believe that high demand and low supply will continue to define our market early on in 2021: Pending transactions are up 51.9% year over year—what a jolt! It seems that as soon as properties hit our market, they go under contract. Super-low interest rates haven’t gone away, either; buyers still have ample incentive to jump into our market and lock in a stellar rate to save thousands of dollars over the life of their loan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s an inverse relationship; whenever our listing inventory is down, our sales increase.%20http://localhost:4000/where-did-2020-leave-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s an inverse relationship; whenever our listing inventory is down, our sales increase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As of January 15, Freddie Mac’s website advertised a 30-year fixed mortgage at 2.6% (2.16% for a 15-year).&lt;/strong&gt; As far as we can tell, rates still seem to be trending downward (or, at the very least, haven’t begun marching back up yet), but we’ll be keeping a close eye on them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about any of these numbers or want to know more about where our market might be headed, please feel free to reach out via phone or email. We would love to hear how we can help you with your 2021 real estate needs or simply be a trusted local resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 15:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-did-2020-leave-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/where-did-2020-leave-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Is Our Florida Keys Market So Busy?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/orIshKIp2eE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m sure you’ve heard, our residential Florida Keys real estate market has been extremely busy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pending transactions are up tremendously. We’re even on pace to break a record this year; we haven’t seen numbers like this since 2004. This is partially attributable to the fact that everything shut down for a couple of months earlier in the year and created a rush of pent-up demand. Interest rates are also extremely low, which is increasing buyers’ purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We’re on pace to break a record this year; we haven’t seen numbers like this since 2004.%20http://localhost:4000/why-is-our-florida-keys-market-so-busy.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We’re on pace to break a record this year; we haven’t seen numbers like this since 2004.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s a quick statistical overview comparing the first nine months of this year to the first nine months of 2019 (based on all property types):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sales increased 7% from 2,177 to 2,329&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average sale price rose 6.4% from $620,338 to $660,216—we’ve seen many properties fetch multiple offers and close near their original list price, which has aided this increase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average list price rose 8.9% from $981,021 to $1,067,918&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average days on market rose 2.5% from 120 to 123 days—we’re a big secondary-home market, so this metric can change depending on when buyers are in our market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The properties for sale dropped 10.3% from 2,318 to 2,080&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When inventory drops like this, it creates demand and boosts sales.&lt;/strong&gt; Also contributing to this demand are low interest rates. I recently checked, and Freddie Mac is offering rates as low as 2.81% for a 30-year fixed mortgage. This has greatly increased buyers’ purchasing power. Getting a mortgage rate that low means more money goes toward the principal than the interest itself. If you’d like to dive deeper into the Keys-wide market stats, you can view the Coldwell Banker Schmitt’s Real Estate Report &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Lela+Ashkarian/Lela+and+Natalie+Fall+2020+CBS+Real+Estate+Report+final.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about our Florida Keys market or are thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to call or email me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 16:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-is-our-florida-keys-market-so-busy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-is-our-florida-keys-market-so-busy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Do You Write a Competitive Offer?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ke988Sqg3EA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For homebuyers, the market is very competitive. Low inventory and high demand mean that most available homes on the market are experiencing multiple-offer situations. So if you’re in the market to buy a home, you’ll need to make your offer stand out in the crowd. Here are six tips to help give your offer a more competitive edge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Submit a larger earnest money deposit.&lt;/strong&gt; If you submit a larger earnest money deposit as a sign of good faith, you’ll show the seller how serious you are about buying the property. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get pre-approved.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re only pre-qualified, that means that your lender hasn’t really looked at your financial history in depth. However, a pre-approval is a signal that you’ve submitted all the required paperwork for a loan and that you could potentially close on the home within a couple of weeks, as long as an appraisal is done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Be flexible with the closing date.&lt;/strong&gt; When in a multiple-offer situation, have your agent reach out to the seller’s agent to ask what the seller may want. Do they need extra time or are they looking to move quickly? Basing the closing date on the seller’s comfort puts the seller in the driver’s seat, which will, in turn, make them more comfortable proceeding into the deal with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Shorten contingencies.&lt;/strong&gt; Typically, that refers to the inspection and financing periods. The standard inspection period in our area is 15 days, and if you’re competing with other buyers, it’s sometimes in your best interest to shorten that time frame. However, don’t shorten it too much; you still want to be able to get the inspection done. The same is true of your financing contingency; shorten the period, but confer with your lender before doing so, as they’ve been very busy this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Make it personal.&lt;/strong&gt; Write a ‘love letter’ to the seller that details why you fell in love with their home and what your family plans to do with it once you move in. You can even include a picture of your family to maybe tug on the seller’s heartstrings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Make your best offer first.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t submit an offer for less than their asking price just to leave room for negotiations. Instead, put your best foot forward from the very beginning. With as many buyers that are in the market, you can’t afford to hope that the seller’s agent will come back and ask for another offer; they’ll likely just pass you over for an offer with a better price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about purchasing a home here in the Florida Keys, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 16:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-write-a-competitive-offer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-how-do-you-write-a-competitive-offer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Are the Top 5 Reasons to Sell Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RX34aBItg3Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now may be the best time to sell your home in our Florida Keys market, and there are five reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Buyer demand is back with a vengeance, both nationally and locally.&lt;/strong&gt; During the shelter-in-place period, a lot of potential buyers took the opportunity to research homes online. Once the stay-at-home orders were lifted, home sales in May shot up 44.3% month over month. When the Keys reopened for visitors on June 1, we saw even higher buyer demand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Inventory remains low.&lt;/strong&gt; On a national scale, inventory in June was down 27% year over year. Here in the Keys, inventory dropped 12.2% year over year. When supply goes down, demand goes up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The shelter-in-place period redefined what buyers want in a house.%20http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-the-top-5-reasons-to-sell-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The shelter-in-place period redefined what buyers want in a house.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Prices are rising.&lt;/strong&gt; In June, prices rose 5.9% year over year from $619,00 to $650,000. Nationally, they rose 7.7%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Mortgage rates are extremely low.&lt;/strong&gt; As of August 10, interest rates for a 30-year fixed-rate mortgage from Freddie Mac were just 2.88%. These historically low rates are encouraging those who’ve been thinking about buying to make their move now because they’ll have fewer payments going toward their interest and more toward their principal. This also increases their spending power. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Homebuyers’ needs have changed.&lt;/strong&gt; Some are looking to upgrade, while others are looking for their first or second home. In any case, the shelter-in-place period redefined what buyers want in a house. A lot of people are still working from home, and their kids are going to school virtually for the first few months of the school year, which means they want more space for home offices and schoolwork areas. They also want bigger backyards. On top of that, destinations have changed; demand is high in our marketplace, for instance, because we’re a tropical retreat area that you can drive to instead of flying. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to start the home buying process or have any real estate questions at all, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 15:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-the-top-5-reasons-to-sell-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-are-the-top-5-reasons-to-sell-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Important Change to the ROGO Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wkbVurorxLc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this year, permits for new buildings in Monroe County were set to expire by 2023, as mandated by the state. This February, however, change in the ROGO process or Unincorporated Monroe County adopts an ordinance for new building permits. That doesn’t mean we’re getting more building permits; it just means they’re going to allocate less per quarter than they have in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Unincorporated Monroe County adopted an ordinance that extends building permits until 2026.%20http://localhost:4000/an-important-change-to-the-rogo-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Unincorporated Monroe County adopted an ordinance that extends building permits until 2026.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over four allocations periods in unincorporated Monroe County, they would previously allocate about 126 permits, which were divided between the upper and lower Keys, as well as Big Pine Key and No Name Key. For example, each year, Big Pine and No Name Keys got eight permits. &lt;strong&gt;Under this new ordinance, that number will be cut down to four, or one every allocation period.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cuts for these permits began on July 13, 2020,&lt;/strong&gt; and we are currently in that first allocation period, which should come out in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is going to be interesting to watch as it plays out. If you have any questions with regard to the ROGO (Rate of Growth Ordinance) process and new construction building here in the Keys, please feel free to reach out to us. We have all the resources you need to help guide you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-important-change-to-the-rogo-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-important-change-to-the-rogo-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Key to Buying &amp; Selling Right Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ThoJWcN4QBk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you have heard plenty from the news about the current state of affairs in the real estate and mortgage market and formed your own opinion by now. I’m curious—what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; your opinion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal with today’s message is to impart a deeper understanding of exactly what it would take to get your home sold in today’s ‘new world.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you have some important things that you want to accomplish. I would love to arrange a consultation with you to hear about your unique situation. After listening to you talk a little bit about your circumstances, I believe I’ll know how best to help you. To make absolutely sure my services are the right fit, I will ask you a few questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I listen to your answers, I’ll let you know immediately if I don’t think I’m the right consultant to help you. Before I ask you those thought-provoking questions though, I will show you how I work, and if you don’t think you’re the right client for my consulting service, please let me know immediately as well. Sound fair enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s really important to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest chunk of our time is spent discovering what is really important to buyers and sellers about the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will ask you some thought-provoking questions to help you discover what is valuable to you. I have learned that when your values are clear, your choices are easy. Now, maybe you’re already clear about what you want to achieve, and if that’s the case, then I can suggest to you what your best options may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your options?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a strong opinion about what is best for our clients; I will always share with you what we believe to be your best options &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, we can narrow your options down to four different directions you can take; we will explore all four when we meet. After we are clear on what’s important to you, and you know what options are available, then I will share with you what we do, how we do it, and for whom we’ve been able to do it in the past. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes our approach different? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is truly important in today’s marketplace is a good, honest education about what homes are selling and what homes have just been listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience shows that the homes that sell seem to have five things in common:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The homeowner is inspired to sell their home.&lt;/strong&gt; In today’s ‘new world,’ with less than a 12-month supply of homes for sale, a homeowner can no longer expect to just list their home and have buyers flocking to the doorstep like it was in the ‘old world.’ At our initial consultation, we will explore whether this is the right time for you to sell and if you have enough motivation to compete with all the other homes currently on the market.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The homeowner is clear about the 30-, 60-, and 90-day time-testing price strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; After discovering what is really important to you, I will suggest a 30-day price, a 60-day price, or a 90-day price. It’s important to realize that the price of your home determines how fast or how slow it will get sold.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The homeowner is aware of the Best In Class Strategy, or BIC.&lt;/strong&gt; The BIC is a method we use to get the home in the condition that makes it most salable. The homeowners who focus on getting their home in BIC condition sell quickest and for the highest current market value.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The homeowner is willing to remove all obstacles standing in the way of the home sale.&lt;/strong&gt; In the ‘new world,’ the homeowner who seriously wants to sell their home must be ready at all times to creatively market and show the home and negotiate all offers.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The homeowner is willing to help get the word out.&lt;/strong&gt; Although I will do 90% of all the marketing for you, I will need some help on your end. There are a few simple things you can do to help spread the news that you are selling your house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this process or real estate in general, please reach out via phone or email. We would love to help you in any way we can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 15:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-buying-selling-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-key-to-buying-selling-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Update on the Florida Keys Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lJtIvevruIg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope all is well with you and your family as we continue to navigate what’s going on in the world. We’re taking things day by day, but we wanted to give you an update on what’s been happening here in the Keys as of late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of last Monday, most non-essential businesses here in the Keys were allowed to reopen at a 25% capacity. This means that restaurants, retail stores, and more are opening back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for our real estate market, things are going very well. We’re a big second home market so we’re used to coordinating virtual showings, but we’ve been implementing Facetime and Zoom into our business as well. &lt;strong&gt;This technology has allowed us to have at least one home go under contract every week since the beginning of April.&lt;/strong&gt; Showing properties with masks on is a little strange, but we’re taking every necessary precaution to help protect our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Home sales were up and inventory was down in the first quarter.%20http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-florida-keys-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Home sales were up and inventory was down in the first quarter.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of homeowners are deciding to take their homes off of the market temporarily, but this is leaving the door open for other homeowners to take advantage of. We have strong demand from buyers in the marketplace right now because of low-interest rates, and those who chose to list now can take advantage of that fact. We’re making it really easy for homebuyers to buy virtually right now and you could sell your home without ever having to bring a buyer inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this new process and how you can take advantage of the current conditions, schedule a time to talk with Ashkarian/Ardis Team, 305-395-0814/305-481-3317, Monday - Friday from 9:00-2:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click HERE → &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/lelarealtor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://calendly.com/lelarealtor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stats that just came out showed us that home sales were up by 3.2% in the first quarter of this year as our listings dropped by nearly 10%. Our days on market remained pretty flat, from 124 to 120. As of May 7, we have seen 17 listings come on the market, seven homes go under contract, and three home sales close in just one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re still here, working, and happy to support you and your real estate goals.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’d like to schedule a meeting or showing or if you have any questions for us, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-florida-keys-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-quick-update-on-the-florida-keys-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
